# **Renjith Rajakumar**

🔀 renjithkumar993@gmail.com 📞 5195961111 💡 50 Sylvya crt Fredericton NB

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/renjith-rajakumar-109a4051/ https://github.com/Renjithkumar993

https://portfolio-renjith.herokuapp.com/

#### **Profile**

As a transitioning IT professional with a strong passion for full-stack development, I have been diligently acquiring expertise in various front-end and back-end technologies. My skill set includes HTML/CSS/Git, JavaScript, Bootstrap, the DOM, APIs, JQuery, JSON, AJAX, Node, ES6, Express, MySQL, MVC, Sequelize, Progressive Web Apps, React, NoSQL, MERN Stack, and computer science fundamentals.

With over 7 years of experience in IT, specializing in managing systems like SCCM, Azure, Exchange, and Security, I bring a unique perspective to full-stack development. I have worked with diverse clients, from small businesses to large enterprises, and hold certifications such as CHFI, CEH, and Microsoft Certified: Azure Security Engineer Associate.

I am a proactive collaborator, well-versed in Agile development and project demonstration. My passion lies in full-stack development, and I am confident that my extensive IT background, coupled with my comprehensive skills, will make me a valuable asset to any team.

#### **Skills**

- Cybersecurity System Administration Powershell Incident Management
- SCCM Microsoft Azure Office 365
- ◆ Progressive Web Apps ◆ React ◆ NoSQL ◆
  MERN Stack ◆ Computer science fundamentals
- Microsoft Exchange Ethical Hacking Linux
- ◆ HTML/CSS/Git ◆ JavaScript ◆ Bootstrap ◆ The
  DOM ◆ APIs ◆ JQuery ◆Testing ◆ Agile
  development ◆ JSON ◆ AJAX ◆ Agile
  development
- NET● Node ES6 Object-oriented programming Express MySQL MVC paradigm Sequelize Bulma

## **Professional Experience**

05/2019 – present Fredericton, Canada

## **Infrastructure Application Analyst**

Service Newbrunswick

- Provide customer service to SNB clients spanning Part 1 (core government departments) and Part 3 (Regional Health Authorities).
- Support the implementation of the Office 365 solution for Exchange and Skype for Business, Cloud Computing.
- Migrate users from Exchange 2010 to Office 365.
- Performing eDiscovery, Mail trace, and troubleshooting emails going to spam and quarantine.
- Recovering soft-deleted mailboxes in an Exchange Hybrid scenario.
- Performed public folder migration.
- Make firewall changes to make the application communicate.

- Assigning Office 365 License according to users' eligibility.
- Provide service to SNB clients and ensure processes and procedures are aligned to the SNB shared services delivery model;
- Monitor the performance of the infrastructure applications and make recommendations for improvement;
- Respond and process Exchange and/or Active Directory support tickets;
- Worked with the SNB Service Desk to establish user management standard operating procedures;
- Assist in the creation and modification of existing user account policies in relation to Office365
- Support the user experience and resolve issues and address concerns

2018 – 2019 Moncton, Canada

## **Technical Operator**

Service Newbrunswick

- Design and implement application deployment strategies, including the use of collections and task sequences for both Office 365 and other applications.
- Collaborate with other IT teams to identify and prioritize application deployment needs.
- Create and maintain deployment packages for Office 365 applications and other business-critical applications.
- Troubleshoot and resolve deployment-related issues.
- Provide guidance and support to end users on the use of Office 365 applications and other deployed applications.
- Monitor and maintain the overall health of the deployment infrastructure.
- Work with other IT teams to ensure compliance with security and regulatory requirements for application deployment.
- Keep up-to-date with new Office 365 application features and updates, and plan for their deployment within the organization.
- Create and maintain documentation and procedures related to application deployment.
- Provide training to end-users and IT staff on the use of Office 365 applications and other deployed applications.

2018 – 2019 Saintjohn, canada

## **Information Technology Support Analyst**

Wyndham World Wide

- Provided technical guidance for migration, configuration and deployment of Lync.
- Daily provided hands-on administration and maintenance of network equipment including routers and switches. Installed and configures computer equipment with operating systems (OS) and applied
- required software policies and standards to adhere with the company IT security policies.
- Assist in the management and maintenance of the Exchange environment, including Exchange on-premises and Exchange Online.
- Monitor and troubleshoot Exchange-related issues and work with senior administrators to resolve them in a timely manner.
- Assist in the implementation of security and compliance measures for the Exchange environment.
- Provided technical support for corporate users to include setting up computers, user name login credentials, passwords, rights, roles and responsibilities using Active Directory (Computers and Users).
- Notified customer of issue status and followed-up with customers to ensure problems have been resolved satisfactorily and in a timely manner.
- Create and maintain documentation and procedures related to Exchange.

2016 – 2017 Saintjohn, Canada

### **Technical Support Specialist**

Nordia Inc

- Provided software troubleshooting and administration for proprietary software as well as Microsoft Office, Windows 7, Internet Explorer, Java, and Adobe.
- Multitasked across multiple platforms, supporting various programs; technically inclined to navigate
- through several systems to get first call resolution in a timely and orderly fashion.
- Developed rapport with the customer early in the contact, by speaking clearly and concisely, asking excellent probing questions, and ensuring clear understanding of what they need assistance with. Take ownership of their issue.
- Maintained customer records by updating account information.
- Troubleshooting system and network problems and diagnosing and solving hardware software issues.

# **Technical Support Specialist**

**Transcom** 

- Provide first-level technical support to end-users via phone, email, and chat.
- Troubleshoot and resolve hardware and software issues related to desktop computers, laptops, printers, and other IT-related equipment.
- Log and track all incoming incidents and requests in a service management system.
- Follow established service level agreements (SLAs) and incident management procedures.
- Provide guidance and support to end-users on the use of IT-related systems and applications.
- Escalate incidents and requests to the appropriate IT teams as needed.
- Keep accurate and detailed records of all incidents and requests.
- Provide end-user training on IT-related systems and applications.
- Work with other IT teams to ensure compliance with security and regulatory requirements for IT-related systems and applications.
- Keep up-to-date with new IT-related systems and applications and provide guidance on their use.
- Create and maintain documentation and procedures related to IT-related systems and applications.

#### **Certificates**

- CompTIA Project+ Certification
  - CompTIA
- Computer Hacking Forensic Investigator (CHFI) - EC-Council
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Security Engineer Associate -Microsoft
- .NET programming 1 year certificate
- Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH) -EC-Council

#### **Education**

2010 – 2013 Coimbatore, India Bachelor of computer application, Computer Programming, Specific Applications

Bharathiar University

2014 – 2016 Sarnia, Canada PG Diploma in Information Technology Professional, Network and System Administration/Administrator

Lambton college

01/2023 Fredericton, Canada **UNB Coding Bootcamp** *University of NewBrunswick*